Nethra Mugala

Nethra.af68@gmail.com | (937) 516 2193 | Miami, FL 33126

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nethra-65b58485/ | https://nethraui.github.io/myportfolio.github.io/



SUMMARY

Experienced in object-oriented programming, developing, testing, debugging code and designing interfaces. Developed web applications from scratch using HTML, CSS, JavaScript frameworks like Angular, Dojo on the frontend and Java RESTful web services on the backend. Capable of learning quick and master new technologies. Strong troubleshooting and problem-solving skills with an analytical mindset.

EDUCATION

Wright State University - Fairborn, OH

2016 - 2018

Master's: Computer Engineering

G. Narayanamma Institute of Technology and Science, INDIA

2012 - 2016

Bachelor's: Electronics and Communication Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, RESTful Web services, J2EE, JAX-RS, Microservices, Spring, Bootstrap,

Dojo, Angular, Node.js

Programming Languages: Java, C, C++, Python.

Databases: Oracle, IBM DB2, MySQL, MongoDB, Server, Firebase Database.

Version Controls: Bitbucket, SourceTree, Git, SVN, CVS.

Applications/Tools: IBM Rational Application Developer (RAD), Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ, WebSphere, IBM Http server,

Tomcat, Postman, SQL Developer, JIRA, Jenkins, UCD, Confluence

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer | NextEra Energy - Miami, FL

May 2019 - Current

- Improved user experience measured by an increase in customer satisfaction by 25% by developing web application using HTML, CSS, JavaScript with Angular, Dojo frameworks.
- Built *RESTful APIs using Java* to export the data to external application.
- Implemented webpage migration from Struts to Dojo framework to make it work on multiple devices, saved development time by separating server-side and client-side coding and *optimized the page reload time by 50%*.
- Developed new application using *Spring framework* and deployed to *AWS cloud* using *Elastic Beanstalk*.
- Launched 3 new features into production in a span of 2 months. Managed milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Developed reusable components to use across projects which reduced rework for developers by 15%.
- Used *JIRA* for workflow visualization, issue tracking, change and release management. Created *Confluence* pages for project and CI/CD process related information.
- Created *Jenkins* multibranch pipelines and automated build and deployments. Created repositories and branches in *Bitbucket* for source code storage and maintenance.
- Consulted with Product Manager to identify minimal viable product and decomposed feature set into small scoped user stories.

$Software\ Developer\ Intern\ |\ Tres\ Mercari\ Group, India$

March 2016 - July 2016

- Developed company's page using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript and used jQuery, AJAX via JSON to request data and update the HTML page.
- Oversaw all the stages of Software Development Life Cycle including quality assurance and integration testing.
- Learned software engineering process improvements and best practices.

CERTIFICATIONS

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

PROJECTS

Covid19 Tracker Built an application in Java using Spring Boot to check covid19 cases for current day by getting the CSV data from a third-party URL.

Pokedex A application developed using React which displays Pokémon and when clicked on it will show all the Pokémon details by getting the Data from third part API called pokeapi.

Real time chat Created a real time chat application using React, Express, Node.js and Socket.io for real time communication.